Welcome back.
欢迎回来
In the previous unit, we went over the basics of probability theory and
在前面的单元中 我们学习了概率论的基本概念
saw how a Bayes network could concisely represent
了解贝叶斯网络如何准确表现
a joint probability distribution,
组合概率分布
including the representation of independence between the variable.
包括展现变量之间的独立性
In this unit, we will see how to do probabilistic inference.
在这个单元中 我们将学习如何进行概率推理
That is, how to answer probability questions using Bayes Nets.
即如何使用贝叶斯网络回答概率问题
Let's put up a simple Bayes net.
我们首先构建一个简单的贝叶斯网络
We'll use the familiar example of the earthquake,
使用地震类似的例子
where we can have a burglary or an earthquake setting of the alarm.
其中我们包括盗窃 地震和设置闹钟
And if the alarm goes off, either John or Mary might call.
如果闹钟响起 约翰或玛丽可能打来电话
Now, what kinds of questions can we ask to do inference about?
那么我们可以在推理时提出哪些问题呢？
The simplest type of question is the same question we ask with an ordinary
最简单的问题类型是我们提问
subroutine or function in a programming language.
程序语言中的普通子程序或函数
Namely, given some inputs, what are the outputs?
即根据一些输入 输出什么？
So in this case, we could say,
所以在这个例子中 可以说
given the inputs of B and E, what are the outputs?
鉴于输入 B 和 E 输出是什么？
J and M, rather than call them input and output variable,
在概率推理中 J 和 M 不是输入和输出变量
in probabilistic inference, we'll call them evidence and query variables.
我们把它们称作证据变量和查询变量
That is the variables that we know the values of are the evidence.
这是我们了解值的变量 称为证据变量
And the ones that we want to find out the values of, are the query variables.
这是我们想要找到值的变量 称为查询变量
Anything that is neither evidence nor query is known as a hidden variable.
既不是证据变量 也不是查询变量的称为隐变量
That is, we won't tell you what its value is,
换句话说 我们不会告诉你值
we won't figure out what its value is and report it.
也不会找出它的值 进行输出
But we'll have to compute with it internally.
我们只是利用这个变量进行内部计算
And now, furthermore, in probabilistic inference,
另外在概率推理中
the output is not a single number for each of the query variables.
输出不只是查询变量
But rather it's a probability distribution.
不过这是一个概率分布
So the answer is going to be a complete joint probability distribution over
所以答案是联合概率分布除以
the query variables.
查询变量
We call this the posterior distribution, given the evidence.
我们把它称作基于证据的后验分布
And we can write it like this.
我们可以这样写
It's the probability distribution of one or
这是一个或多个查询变量的概率分布
more query variables given the values of the evidence variables.
基于证据变量的值
And there can be 0 or more evidence variables, and
可以有 0 个或多个证据变量
each of them are given an exact value.
每个证据变量都赋予了确切值
And that's the computation we want to come up with.
这是我们要提出的计算
There's another question we can ask, which is the most likely explanation.
我们还要提问另一个问题 可能是最合理的解释
That is, out of all the possible values for all the query variables,
在查询变量所有可能的值中
which combination of values has the highest probability.
哪个值组合得到最大的概率
We write the formula like this asking which Q values are maxable,
我们写出这样的公式 提问哪个 Q 值最大
given the evidence values.
基于证据值
Now, in an ordinary programming language,
现在在一般程序语言中
each function goes only one way.
每个函数都只有一种方式
It has input variables, does some computation, and
包括输入变量 进行一些计算
comes up with a result variable or result variables.
提出一个或多个结果变量
One great thing about base nets is that we're not restricted to going only in
贝叶斯网络的伟大之处在于我们不受限于
one direction.
一个方向
We could go in the causal direction,
我们可以进行随机方向
giving as evidence the root nodes of the tree and
将证据作为树的根节点
asking as query values the nodes at the bottom.
查询值位于节点的底部
Or we could reverse that causal flow.
或者可以逆转随机流
For example, we could have J and M be the evidence variable and B and
例如我们把 J 和 M 作为证据变量
E be the query variables or we could have any other combination.
B 和 E 作为查询变量 或者进行其他形式的组合
For example, we could have M be the evidence variable.
例如把 M 作为证据变量
And J and B be the query variables.
J 和 B 作为查询变量
Here's a question for you.
这里有个问题
Imagine the situation where Mary has called to report that the alarm is
设想玛丽打电话指出闹铃响起
going off and we want to know whether or not there has been a burglary.
我们想知道是不是因为盗窃
For each of the nodes, click on the circle to tell us if the node
对于每个节点 告诉我们
is an evidence node, a hidden node, or a query node.
哪个是证据节点 哪个是隐藏节点或查询节点 并画上圆圈
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[背景音]最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6